<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Humiliation Is the Most Intense Emotion?	</title>
	<atom:link href="/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/</link>
	<description>BDSM, books and missing links by Xiao Yingtai</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:52:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Humiliation: hotness and hard-limits &#124; Valery North - Writer		</title>
		<link>/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-905</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Humiliation: hotness and hard-limits &#124; Valery North - Writer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3229#comment-905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] Xiao Yingtai @ University of Abject Submission wrote about humiliation after reading a psychology study exploring the emotion. The study defined humiliation as, “publicity and loss of social status”. That sounds a lot like the &#8220;public shame&#8221; scenario I described above, so it&#8217;s hard for me to relate to that definition as it stands. [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Xiao Yingtai @ University of Abject Submission wrote about humiliation after reading a psychology study exploring the emotion. The study defined humiliation as, “publicity and loss of social status”. That sounds a lot like the &#8220;public shame&#8221; scenario I described above, so it&#8217;s hard for me to relate to that definition as it stands. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Kink&#8217;s transgressions: breaking the rules &#124; Valery North - Writer		</title>
		<link>/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-190</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kink&#8217;s transgressions: breaking the rules &#124; Valery North - Writer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 16:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3229#comment-190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] been thinking about where humiliation fits into my kink. Yingtai wrote a piece about research on humiliation (outside of BDSM), where the researchers used a definition of humiliation as, &#8220;the emotion [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] been thinking about where humiliation fits into my kink. Yingtai wrote a piece about research on humiliation (outside of BDSM), where the researchers used a definition of humiliation as, &#8220;the emotion [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Xiao Yingtai		</title>
		<link>/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-113</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xiao Yingtai]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 02:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3229#comment-113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-110&quot;&gt;ValeryNorth&lt;/a&gt;.

I am sorry about the depression voice. I knew it was there, I just think it is also sensible in this respect. I am beginning to think humiliation is a fairly complex emotion, combining anger and shame (or something in that neighbourhood). So I would hazard a guess that depression can stop people from having enough ego to feel they have the right to be angry?

Thinking about humiliation play in BDSM, I guess publicity is not the best word, because you don&#039;t need an audience, you only need one other person there. But it&#039;s certainly not an emotion I can feel without external help, unlike shame, which is what I think they were trying to get at.

You have also made me wonder if humiliation is a word that we use for more than one thing. Maybe it doesn&#039;t just subjectively refer to an emotional reaction, but also objectively to the kind of situation that makes most people feel that way (but not all)?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-110">ValeryNorth</a>.</p>
<p>I am sorry about the depression voice. I knew it was there, I just think it is also sensible in this respect. I am beginning to think humiliation is a fairly complex emotion, combining anger and shame (or something in that neighbourhood). So I would hazard a guess that depression can stop people from having enough ego to feel they have the right to be angry?</p>
<p>Thinking about humiliation play in BDSM, I guess publicity is not the best word, because you don&#8217;t need an audience, you only need one other person there. But it&#8217;s certainly not an emotion I can feel without external help, unlike shame, which is what I think they were trying to get at.</p>
<p>You have also made me wonder if humiliation is a word that we use for more than one thing. Maybe it doesn&#8217;t just subjectively refer to an emotional reaction, but also objectively to the kind of situation that makes most people feel that way (but not all)?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: ValeryNorth		</title>
		<link>/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-110</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ValeryNorth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 04:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3229#comment-110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-109&quot;&gt;Xiao Yingtai&lt;/a&gt;.

I was trying to think through what my distinction between &quot;shame&quot; and &quot;humiliation&quot; was, and couldn&#039;t find one that correctly sorted the scenarios I could think of for each (as you might guess, I&#039;m also not convinced by the researchers&#039; definition of &quot;publicity and loss of social status&quot;!) But I think the scenario as described, of an instant rejection by an internet date, didn&#039;t seem &quot;public&quot;, and also didn&#039;t involve &quot;social status&quot;. No one else knows why either of you are there, so neither &quot;public&quot; nor &quot;status&quot; can be affected.

I tried to think of a scenario to make me feel humiliation, based on the &quot;internet date&quot; theme, and the best I could come up with was arriving and approaching the wrong person by mistake. That still didn&#039;t have the &quot;public&quot; &quot;loss of social status&quot; (you&#039;d need the wrong person to then make it very obvious to everyone else what had just happened - and even then, I would be more affected by my initial mistake than by the public announcement of it).

&quot;Your ego is sensible&quot; - not quite! My reaction to the story has more to do with my history of depression. My &quot;depression voice&quot; still says things like, &quot;you will never have anything good&quot;, &quot;no one really wants you&quot;, &quot;don&#039;t expect any return on your time and effort&quot; - so an internet date turning up and immediately leaving just seems like, &quot;Oh well, I suppose that was the most likely outcome.&quot; (And in the &quot;happy&quot; scenario the &quot;depression voice&quot; is telling me to expect nothing good, reminding me of all the times it hasn&#039;t worked out.) It sounds bleak, but I&#039;m a pretty positive person, a twisted form of &quot;expect the worst, believe in the best&quot;. And good things do actually happen to me from time to time.

As for &quot;elicit different emotions&quot;, I think there are overlapping themes: both &quot;humiliation&quot; and &quot;anger&quot; involve a sense of &quot;picking up the pieces&quot; (literally in &quot;anger&quot;, figuratively in &quot;humiliation&quot;); &quot;happy&quot; and &quot;anger&quot; share a sense of looking to the future (one cautiously, the other assessing what repairs/tidying are needed); &quot;happy&quot; and &quot;humiliation&quot; are both strongly affected by the &quot;depression voice&quot; expecting the worst (again, one cautious, the other resigned).]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-109">Xiao Yingtai</a>.</p>
<p>I was trying to think through what my distinction between &#8220;shame&#8221; and &#8220;humiliation&#8221; was, and couldn&#8217;t find one that correctly sorted the scenarios I could think of for each (as you might guess, I&#8217;m also not convinced by the researchers&#8217; definition of &#8220;publicity and loss of social status&#8221;!) But I think the scenario as described, of an instant rejection by an internet date, didn&#8217;t seem &#8220;public&#8221;, and also didn&#8217;t involve &#8220;social status&#8221;. No one else knows why either of you are there, so neither &#8220;public&#8221; nor &#8220;status&#8221; can be affected.</p>
<p>I tried to think of a scenario to make me feel humiliation, based on the &#8220;internet date&#8221; theme, and the best I could come up with was arriving and approaching the wrong person by mistake. That still didn&#8217;t have the &#8220;public&#8221; &#8220;loss of social status&#8221; (you&#8217;d need the wrong person to then make it very obvious to everyone else what had just happened &#8211; and even then, I would be more affected by my initial mistake than by the public announcement of it).</p>
<p>&#8220;Your ego is sensible&#8221; &#8211; not quite! My reaction to the story has more to do with my history of depression. My &#8220;depression voice&#8221; still says things like, &#8220;you will never have anything good&#8221;, &#8220;no one really wants you&#8221;, &#8220;don&#8217;t expect any return on your time and effort&#8221; &#8211; so an internet date turning up and immediately leaving just seems like, &#8220;Oh well, I suppose that was the most likely outcome.&#8221; (And in the &#8220;happy&#8221; scenario the &#8220;depression voice&#8221; is telling me to expect nothing good, reminding me of all the times it hasn&#8217;t worked out.) It sounds bleak, but I&#8217;m a pretty positive person, a twisted form of &#8220;expect the worst, believe in the best&#8221;. And good things do actually happen to me from time to time.</p>
<p>As for &#8220;elicit different emotions&#8221;, I think there are overlapping themes: both &#8220;humiliation&#8221; and &#8220;anger&#8221; involve a sense of &#8220;picking up the pieces&#8221; (literally in &#8220;anger&#8221;, figuratively in &#8220;humiliation&#8221;); &#8220;happy&#8221; and &#8220;anger&#8221; share a sense of looking to the future (one cautiously, the other assessing what repairs/tidying are needed); &#8220;happy&#8221; and &#8220;humiliation&#8221; are both strongly affected by the &#8220;depression voice&#8221; expecting the worst (again, one cautious, the other resigned).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Xiao Yingtai		</title>
		<link>/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-109</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xiao Yingtai]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3229#comment-109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-108&quot;&gt;ValeryNorth&lt;/a&gt;.

It&#039;s always good to hear from you! What you say makes sense, but that&#039;s more about what labels to apply to the three scenarios. It sounds like they do still elicit different emotions from you?

The researchers mention that they consider publicity and loss of social status to be essential components of humiliation. I&#039;m curious if that would be part of your reaction to the &#039;humiliation&#039; scenario. If so, maybe your ego is just sensible enough not to react the way others might.

My first concern was that the stories might not be controlled for emotional intensity. So I was happy that the researchers checked that by asking people for ratings afterwards.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-108">ValeryNorth</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s always good to hear from you! What you say makes sense, but that&#8217;s more about what labels to apply to the three scenarios. It sounds like they do still elicit different emotions from you?</p>
<p>The researchers mention that they consider publicity and loss of social status to be essential components of humiliation. I&#8217;m curious if that would be part of your reaction to the &#8216;humiliation&#8217; scenario. If so, maybe your ego is just sensible enough not to react the way others might.</p>
<p>My first concern was that the stories might not be controlled for emotional intensity. So I was happy that the researchers checked that by asking people for ratings afterwards.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: ValeryNorth		</title>
		<link>/humiliation-is-the-most-intense-emotion/#comment-108</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ValeryNorth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 23:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3229#comment-108</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Interesting report. I always wonder how they calibrate the stimuli for these types of research though. For instance, the three scenarios given would not, for me, elicit the emotions assigned to them. The first one would provoke resignation and disappointment, maybe confusion, but not humiliation (there&#039;s a relationship with my depression, incidentally); the second would provoke frustration and sadness, but the closest to anger would be &quot;exasperation&quot; (which might all come across as &quot;passive-aggressive&quot;). The third would provoke excitement, nervousness and hope but not &quot;happiness&quot; (except inasmuch as hope is a happy state, I suppose). Happiness would wait until we discovered a bit more in common!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Interesting report. I always wonder how they calibrate the stimuli for these types of research though. For instance, the three scenarios given would not, for me, elicit the emotions assigned to them. The first one would provoke resignation and disappointment, maybe confusion, but not humiliation (there&#8217;s a relationship with my depression, incidentally); the second would provoke frustration and sadness, but the closest to anger would be &#8220;exasperation&#8221; (which might all come across as &#8220;passive-aggressive&#8221;). The third would provoke excitement, nervousness and hope but not &#8220;happiness&#8221; (except inasmuch as hope is a happy state, I suppose). Happiness would wait until we discovered a bit more in common!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
