<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Submissive Strength: Contradiction or Koan?	</title>
	<atom:link href="/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/</link>
	<description>BDSM, books and missing links by Xiao Yingtai</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 08:01:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: ValeryNorth		</title>
		<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-1011</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ValeryNorth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 01:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5884#comment-1011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-1006&quot;&gt;Xiao Yingtai&lt;/a&gt;.

Probably. To quote a phrase from our other misunderstanding thread, &quot;I experienced too much of that kind of pain&quot; - so I probably can&#039;t grok what you&#039;re using the word to describe. To quote myself, &quot;qualities rather than judgements&quot; - worthiness can&#039;t ever be freed from the latter, but we probably agree about desirable qualities (and recognising that anyone can fall short of them, however &quot;good&quot; they are).]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-1006">Xiao Yingtai</a>.</p>
<p>Probably. To quote a phrase from our other misunderstanding thread, &#8220;I experienced too much of that kind of pain&#8221; &#8211; so I probably can&#8217;t grok what you&#8217;re using the word to describe. To quote myself, &#8220;qualities rather than judgements&#8221; &#8211; worthiness can&#8217;t ever be freed from the latter, but we probably agree about desirable qualities (and recognising that anyone can fall short of them, however &#8220;good&#8221; they are).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Xiao Yingtai		</title>
		<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-1006</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xiao Yingtai]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5884#comment-1006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-1005&quot;&gt;ValeryNorth&lt;/a&gt;.

I think we may have to agree to disagree on the word &quot;worthy&quot;. But I think your explanation makes it clear that that doesn&#039;t mean we disagree on the more important things like taking responsibility.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-1005">ValeryNorth</a>.</p>
<p>I think we may have to agree to disagree on the word &#8220;worthy&#8221;. But I think your explanation makes it clear that that doesn&#8217;t mean we disagree on the more important things like taking responsibility.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: ValeryNorth		</title>
		<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-1005</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ValeryNorth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 23:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5884#comment-1005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-998&quot;&gt;Xiao Yingtai&lt;/a&gt;.

&#062; &quot;I feel very strongly that one has to be worthy of power.&quot;

I find this statement very troubling. I think for me &quot;worthy&quot; is too close a synonym of &quot;deserving&quot; or &quot;owed&quot;, which in turn leads to a key problem with privilege, namely, &quot;entitlement&quot;. That in turn is linked to the conception of women as the &quot;gatekeepers&quot; of sex, who are supposed to grant it only to &quot;worthy&quot; men (and if they choose men deemed &quot;unworthy&quot;, it goes bad for the women, with slut-shaming at the bottom end of that range of punishments).

So to say, &quot;be worthy of power&quot; or &quot;be worthy of privilege&quot; - well, that line of thinking when I was younger led me down the &quot;Nice Guyism&quot; path. The only way to win is not to play, but instead to be the best me I can be without reference to &quot;worthy&quot; or &quot;deserving&quot;.

I think &lt;a href=&quot;https://valerynorth.wordpress.com/2013/04/15/the-looking-for-lists/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; probably captures a lot of the rest of the problems I have with the idea of &quot;worthy&quot; as a requirement.

The final thing is that it seems to create a barrier to human interaction: just as &quot;don&#039;t even try to date if you&#039;re suffering from depression&quot; - if you&#039;re short of some &quot;worthiness&quot; standard, don&#039;t bother trying to be a Dom? In either case, I would be condemned to a life of solitude and loneliness. But by not worrying about &quot;worthy&quot; I was able to cast off guilt and accept responsibility. By not worrying about &quot;depression&quot; I was able to just get on with not letting it control or ruin my life.

&#062; &quot;So I’m really hoping we just have different associations with the word ‘worthy’?&quot;

Put bluntly, my association of the term &quot;worthy&quot; is wrapped up in its negation, which translates as, &quot;all the reasons why you&#039;re not allowed to be happy&quot;. Hence choosing to opt out of the game.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-998">Xiao Yingtai</a>.</p>
<p>&gt; &#8220;I feel very strongly that one has to be worthy of power.&#8221;</p>
<p>I find this statement very troubling. I think for me &#8220;worthy&#8221; is too close a synonym of &#8220;deserving&#8221; or &#8220;owed&#8221;, which in turn leads to a key problem with privilege, namely, &#8220;entitlement&#8221;. That in turn is linked to the conception of women as the &#8220;gatekeepers&#8221; of sex, who are supposed to grant it only to &#8220;worthy&#8221; men (and if they choose men deemed &#8220;unworthy&#8221;, it goes bad for the women, with slut-shaming at the bottom end of that range of punishments).</p>
<p>So to say, &#8220;be worthy of power&#8221; or &#8220;be worthy of privilege&#8221; &#8211; well, that line of thinking when I was younger led me down the &#8220;Nice Guyism&#8221; path. The only way to win is not to play, but instead to be the best me I can be without reference to &#8220;worthy&#8221; or &#8220;deserving&#8221;.</p>
<p>I think <a href="https://valerynorth.wordpress.com/2013/04/15/the-looking-for-lists/" rel="nofollow">this post</a> probably captures a lot of the rest of the problems I have with the idea of &#8220;worthy&#8221; as a requirement.</p>
<p>The final thing is that it seems to create a barrier to human interaction: just as &#8220;don&#8217;t even try to date if you&#8217;re suffering from depression&#8221; &#8211; if you&#8217;re short of some &#8220;worthiness&#8221; standard, don&#8217;t bother trying to be a Dom? In either case, I would be condemned to a life of solitude and loneliness. But by not worrying about &#8220;worthy&#8221; I was able to cast off guilt and accept responsibility. By not worrying about &#8220;depression&#8221; I was able to just get on with not letting it control or ruin my life.</p>
<p>&gt; &#8220;So I’m really hoping we just have different associations with the word ‘worthy’?&#8221;</p>
<p>Put bluntly, my association of the term &#8220;worthy&#8221; is wrapped up in its negation, which translates as, &#8220;all the reasons why you&#8217;re not allowed to be happy&#8221;. Hence choosing to opt out of the game.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Xiao Yingtai		</title>
		<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-999</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xiao Yingtai]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 01:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5884#comment-999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-948&quot;&gt;Malin James&lt;/a&gt;.

Have you had time to digest? :-) I&#039;m actually a little surprised because I see those things as much more relevant to submission. Domming, at least the &lt;a href=&quot;/am-i-just-selfish-service-versus-control/&quot; title=&quot;Am I Just Selfish? Service Versus Control&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;control-oriented version&lt;/a&gt;, is an active role and there are all kinds of things you can learn to DO. Whereas my frustration in seeking out &lt;a href=&quot;/subs-need-classes-too/&quot; title=&quot;Subs Need Classes Too!&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;education for subs&lt;/a&gt; has been partly assuaged by the realisation that the main thing I need to learn is how to ACCEPT. And most of what we know about that comes from spirituality traditions, it&#039;s not the kind of thing people hold BDSM classes about.

Then again, I can see that mindfulness is useful to everyone! And awareness and compassion are DEFINITELY qualities I want in a dom. So you are right after all!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-948">Malin James</a>.</p>
<p>Have you had time to digest? :-) I&#8217;m actually a little surprised because I see those things as much more relevant to submission. Domming, at least the <a href="/am-i-just-selfish-service-versus-control/" title="Am I Just Selfish? Service Versus Control" rel="nofollow">control-oriented version</a>, is an active role and there are all kinds of things you can learn to DO. Whereas my frustration in seeking out <a href="/subs-need-classes-too/" title="Subs Need Classes Too!" rel="nofollow">education for subs</a> has been partly assuaged by the realisation that the main thing I need to learn is how to ACCEPT. And most of what we know about that comes from spirituality traditions, it&#8217;s not the kind of thing people hold BDSM classes about.</p>
<p>Then again, I can see that mindfulness is useful to everyone! And awareness and compassion are DEFINITELY qualities I want in a dom. So you are right after all!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Xiao Yingtai		</title>
		<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-998</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Xiao Yingtai]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 01:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5884#comment-998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-946&quot;&gt;ValeryNorth&lt;/a&gt;.

1) Yes!

2) Maybe this is another area where we would rather use different words for the same thing? Domming is a position of power, and I feel very strongly that one has to be worthy of power. Responsibility, commitment, sheer ability to get the job done. And since masculinity is an identity that carries privilege, I respect those who strive to be worthy of it, who feel a duty to those who don&#039;t have that privilege. That&#039;s part of what I was trying to describe in my post on &lt;a href=&quot;/condescension-or-kindness-from-above/&quot; title=&quot;Condescension, or Kindness from Above&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Condescension or Kindness from Above&lt;/a&gt;. 

It pains me very deeply that I don&#039;t get that vibe from gender relations here in America. It&#039;s much more like men feeling worthy of respect from other men, as you say. It&#039;s almost like people believe so fundamentally in equality here that they cannot bring themselves to accept that they have privilege, and therefore the duty to use it well. What I keep seeing in young men here is that they think they can reject their privilege and interact with women as equals. Hah. Denial is not the answer.

So I&#039;m really hoping we just have different associations with the word &#039;worthy&#039;? And of course I realise you don&#039;t live here and may have a different experience, it just sounds uncannily similar.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-946">ValeryNorth</a>.</p>
<p>1) Yes!</p>
<p>2) Maybe this is another area where we would rather use different words for the same thing? Domming is a position of power, and I feel very strongly that one has to be worthy of power. Responsibility, commitment, sheer ability to get the job done. And since masculinity is an identity that carries privilege, I respect those who strive to be worthy of it, who feel a duty to those who don&#8217;t have that privilege. That&#8217;s part of what I was trying to describe in my post on <a href="/condescension-or-kindness-from-above/" title="Condescension, or Kindness from Above" rel="nofollow">Condescension or Kindness from Above</a>. </p>
<p>It pains me very deeply that I don&#8217;t get that vibe from gender relations here in America. It&#8217;s much more like men feeling worthy of respect from other men, as you say. It&#8217;s almost like people believe so fundamentally in equality here that they cannot bring themselves to accept that they have privilege, and therefore the duty to use it well. What I keep seeing in young men here is that they think they can reject their privilege and interact with women as equals. Hah. Denial is not the answer.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;m really hoping we just have different associations with the word &#8216;worthy&#8217;? And of course I realise you don&#8217;t live here and may have a different experience, it just sounds uncannily similar.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: The non-binary of D/s &#124; Valery North - Writer		</title>
		<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-967</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The non-binary of D/s &#124; Valery North - Writer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 16:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5884#comment-967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] Yingtai discussed D/s as containing koans (Buddhist spiritual conundrums) which also dissolves the duality or binary-ness of D/s. That post [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Yingtai discussed D/s as containing koans (Buddhist spiritual conundrums) which also dissolves the duality or binary-ness of D/s. That post [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Malin James		</title>
		<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-948</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Malin James]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 21:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5884#comment-948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I literally have too many things to say to leave a useful comment. I&#039;m going to have to sit with my thoughts for a bit before I try. Suffice to say, I often think of D/s dynamics as a form of practice - mindfulness, awareness and compassion being critical to my understanding and relationship to dominance. That you explored the apparent contradictions in your relationship to submission in terms of koans resonated to a ridiculous degree. Hence my need to sit the hell down and digest it. It&#039;s just so very much in line with my own instincts, it kind of amazes me.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I literally have too many things to say to leave a useful comment. I&#8217;m going to have to sit with my thoughts for a bit before I try. Suffice to say, I often think of D/s dynamics as a form of practice &#8211; mindfulness, awareness and compassion being critical to my understanding and relationship to dominance. That you explored the apparent contradictions in your relationship to submission in terms of koans resonated to a ridiculous degree. Hence my need to sit the hell down and digest it. It&#8217;s just so very much in line with my own instincts, it kind of amazes me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: ValeryNorth		</title>
		<link>/submissive-strength-contradiction-or-koan/#comment-946</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ValeryNorth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 16:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5884#comment-946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Great post! I like the part you added to the text of your previous comment @ mine, about &quot;make them feel loved&quot;, and I&#039;ve written a new post to discuss that. A couple of quick points to mention here:

1/. I think BDSM, and especially D/s, as a whole tends to function in very koan-like ways (not coming from a Buddhist background, I don&#039;t want to claim they actually are koans as such, but that &quot;apparent contradiction&quot; seems so integral to so much of BDSM, no wonder we love discussing What It Is That We Do so much!) It&#039;s a very spiritual experience, even as casual play, for that reason.

2/. I have quite a troubled relationship with the concept of &quot;worthiness&quot;; I think it can be quite a harmful ideal or objective, especially as it&#039;s wrapped up in the ways masculinity is used to punish men (by other men, especially - feminist-style analysis!) For me a big part of my development on emotional courage and vulnerability has been to become okay with not being, or needing to be, &quot;worthy&quot; (and Lord knows, I&#039;m not there yet!) but accepting what&#039;s offered anyway (as either D or s - which is the other side of the emotional coin from “He’s ignoring me right now, but that’s okay.” and often co-exists with that, I suspect!) So talking about &quot;the dom’s worthiness&quot; seems awkward to me, and I would prefer to see it described in terms of qualities rather than judgements (like Sub strength is a quality, not a judgement)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Great post! I like the part you added to the text of your previous comment @ mine, about &#8220;make them feel loved&#8221;, and I&#8217;ve written a new post to discuss that. A couple of quick points to mention here:</p>
<p>1/. I think BDSM, and especially D/s, as a whole tends to function in very koan-like ways (not coming from a Buddhist background, I don&#8217;t want to claim they actually are koans as such, but that &#8220;apparent contradiction&#8221; seems so integral to so much of BDSM, no wonder we love discussing What It Is That We Do so much!) It&#8217;s a very spiritual experience, even as casual play, for that reason.</p>
<p>2/. I have quite a troubled relationship with the concept of &#8220;worthiness&#8221;; I think it can be quite a harmful ideal or objective, especially as it&#8217;s wrapped up in the ways masculinity is used to punish men (by other men, especially &#8211; feminist-style analysis!) For me a big part of my development on emotional courage and vulnerability has been to become okay with not being, or needing to be, &#8220;worthy&#8221; (and Lord knows, I&#8217;m not there yet!) but accepting what&#8217;s offered anyway (as either D or s &#8211; which is the other side of the emotional coin from “He’s ignoring me right now, but that’s okay.” and often co-exists with that, I suspect!) So talking about &#8220;the dom’s worthiness&#8221; seems awkward to me, and I would prefer to see it described in terms of qualities rather than judgements (like Sub strength is a quality, not a judgement)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
